Jersey city, NJ (929) 365-3391 ryhor.mudrahel@gmail.com *Linkedin Profile*

Ryhor Mudrahel

CAREER PROFILE

Senior Software Backend Engineer with 10+ years of hands-on experience in software development for Hi-Tech, Healthcare and Finance industries.

Core competencies include: software development, implementation, coding, testing, debugging, code review, maintenance, support, agile development, grooming, estimation, communication with dev team and stakeholders, knowledge sharing

Core skills:

Languages: Java 8, SQL, html, xml, css;

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL;

APIs: REST, RESTful Api;

Frameworks: Spring framework, Spring Boot;

CI/CD: Maven, Jenkins;Version control: Git;ORM: Hibernate;Tests: JUnit;

• IDE: Intellij IDEA

Secondary skills: Java core, JEE, relative databases, RDBMS, JPA, Microservices, unit tests, Microsoft Azure cloud, Agile, Scrum, SDLC, OOP, Amazon S3, JIRA

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer (November 2015 - May 2023), **Epam Systems** - *Remote*

- Played a key role in designing, developing and implementing critical parts of Java-based applications using Java 8, Spring Framework and REST APIs.
- Took a part in Full cycle development (SDLC) of many different mid/small sized projects as part of Agile team (Scrum)
- In general worked on enhancement, optimization and support of already existing applications.
- Wrote CRUD queries for MySQL and PostgreSQL dbs and used Hibernate ORM
- Conducted manual and automated testing. Implemented unit tests using jUnit library.
- Troubleshooted and resolved many different technical issues through logs and code analysis.
- Created/Edited several simple web pages using html, xml and css languages
- Implemented simple multithreading logic for faster data processing

- Was exposed to close communication with different teams, stakeholders and end users on daily basis
- Collaborated with business team and product manager through MS Teams and MS Outlook to determine acceptance and success criteria altogether with technical requirements for projects, all stored in OneNote and MS Azure
- Participated in code reviews, estimation and grooming sessions (MS Azure)
- Contributed to development process improvement and optimization. Introduced Intellij IDEA
 IDE to the team, wrote generalized parent .pom for a "family" of projects to reduce time of
 3rd party libraries vulnerability resolution
- CI/CD was Jenkins and Apache Maven

Senior Software Engineer (May 2018 - September 2018) — *New York City, NY*

- Promoted to a Senior Engineer and relocated to the US to work on-site in the client's office as developer and consultant to provide technical support. Jira tickets resolution
- Troubleshooted and fixed plenty of technical issues for premium business clients, mostly related to tech side of already existing applications
- Decreased average time resolution of bug tickets by 15%
- Developed an extensive library of topics addressing common tech issues and bugs in Confluence

Software Engineer (November 2015 - April 2018) — *Minsk, Belarus*

- Played role of a developer and the team leader for a team of five
- Maintained already existing and Implemented new Java-based applications (Java 8,RPA, REST)
- Was responsible for work distribution (Jira), onboarding and knowledge sharing within the team. KB pages maintenance in confluence.
- Kept profile of a developer with highest amount of resolved bug tickets within the team
- Was involved in close communication with business team, client team and stakeholders (status call, demos, daily meetings, etc.)

Software Engineer (July 2013 - October 2015), System Technologies / Belsoft-Borlas

Group — *Minsk*, *Belarus*

- Promoted to Software Engineer
- Took a part in development of Payment Processing Server application for a bank
- Analyzed already existed outdated application to collect list of requirements and metrics
- Wrote technical documentation and implemented payment service prototype
- Mapped business logic to a DB

Junior Software Engineer (July 2013 - December 2014) — Minsk, Belarus

- Implemented an application for electronic flow documents of HR and Payroll (salary calculation, hire/fire an employee, vacation, sick leaves, timesheets, rates, etc.) using Java 6
- Integrated said application with already existed services
- Wrote unit tests (jUnit) to cover critical business logic
- Designed objects in DB and implemented PL/SQL procedures according to business requirements (Oracle DB)
- Wrote CRUD queries to cover business logic

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Engineer (April 2011 - June 2013), **Vitebsk Regional Cardiological Dispensary** — *Vitebsk, Belarus*

EDUCATION

Polotsk State University, Belarus

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science